

#### **CONTACT ME AT**

- München, Germany
- isaac.olguin@tum.de
- github.com/IsaacOlguin
- @isaac-olguin
- isaacolguin.github.io

#### SKILLS SUMMARY

- Software Development
- Database Development and Management
- Requirement analysis
- Systems' design
- Process Improvement
- Teamwork and time management

#### COMMUNICATION SKILLS

- •••• Spanish
- •••• English
- •••• German

## MAIN TECHNOLOGICAL SKILLS

- Java, C, Python, PyTorch
- PostgreSQL, Sybase, MySQL, MongoDB

### INTERESTS

Security, NLP, Artificial Intelligence, Deep Learning, Criptography, Parallel Computing, Quantum Computing, Web Development, Hiking, Films, Running, Volleyball

# ISAAC MISAEL **OLGUÍN NOLASCO**

# M.SC. INFORMATICS STUDENT COMPUTER SCIENCE ENGINEER

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a Master's student and CS engineer with holistic knowledge of software development and design. I have experience in realtime systems and full-stack development in the banking sector. I am trying to merge the Natural Language Processing and Security.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Werkstudent

Siemens Advanta Consulting | April 2022 - Present

Cybersecurity consultant.

Collaboration in the analysis, design, development, and assessment of the app that allows to gather information for the security analysis and the requirements' fulfillment of the Zero Trust Project.

## Systems analyst

Bank of Mexico (Central Bank) | Dec 2015 - Oct 2020

- Analyst and programmer of the Foreign Currency Systems Development
- Collaboration in the analysis, design, and development of:
  - the Interbanking Payment System (SPID®). It allows organizations to make real-time transferences with US dollars in the Mexican territory. I was in charge of the development and maintenance of the DB, monitor's interface, and server applications that give users the possibility to obtain transfer confirmations.
  - the Clearing Houses System. It was designed to provide clearing and settlement of interbank documents, including checks, electronic funds transfers, direct debit operations, and interbank cash operations. I took part in the maintenance and upgrade of the whole system.
  - the Funds Transfer System from the USA to Mexico. It is is a service to send money from an account in a financial institution subscribed to the service in the United States to an account in any participant Mexico. I helped in the maintenance of the system and its communication with the correspondent application of the Federal Reserved in the US.
  - the "Know your Customer's Customer" System. It is designed to process and deliver information that aims to help financial inclusion for sustainable access into the financial market. It considers the responsibility of the central bank against money laundering and combating terrorism. I helped to develop the first version of the WebApp that people and organizations/companies will use to access their information.
  - the Mexican Real-time Gross Settlement (SPEI®). My responsibilities relied on the upgrade of the monitor and its components that users use to operate and control the system.

#### CERTIFICATIONS



**Deep Learning Specialization** Coursera

- Neural Network and Deep Learning (ESFCWTBBS6MD)
- Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter Tuning, Regularization and Optimization
- Convolutional Neural Networks (CSCPPHDY4S2S)



Sentiment Analysis with Deep Learning using BERT

Coursera | NZLN6DURCLR9



Introduction to TensorFlow for Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning

Coursera | 9H9P7279S2X4



**Introduction to Python for Cybersecurity** Coursera | Y76XEPDGU47U



Natural Language Processing with **Classification and Vector Spaces** Coursera | CB3XPT3SNYRJ

#### Achievements:

Most of the systems required the commitment of my team to deliver them according to reduced times. So far they are resilient, stable, and were always delivered before the deadline.

I was in charge of the development of the DB that is used to store all transferences of the SPID system and solved requests from clients in very short periods of time that in general would have taken days to be solved.

## Internship

Bank of Mexico (Central Bank) | Jun 2015 - Dec 2015

Analysis and programming of the web application regarding the Clearing House System. The system was upgraded to its web version and improved the user experience. Besides new cryptographic libraries were embedded to enhance its security.

#### Achievements:

- After three months of the beginning of my internship, I got an offer for a Software developer position in the central bank.
- I was hired by the central bank immediately after the end of my internship.

#### EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

## Technische Universität München, Germany

Masters in Informatik | Oct 2020 - Present

Lectures that I have already taken or I am taking this summer semester 2022:

- Network Security, Networks for Monetary Transactions, and Security Engineering
- Parallel Programming and Introduction to Quantum Computing
- Introduction to Deep Learning, and Legal Data Science and Informatics
- Techniques in Artificial Intelligence
- Seminars: (In)Security of Online Voting Systems & JavaScript Technology
- Praktikums: Advanced Programming Systems in C & Legal Data Analysis Lab

## Instituto Politécnico Nacional, Mexico / Universidad Politécnica de Madrid, Spain

B. Computer Science | Jul 2011 - Dec 2015

GPA: 3 (American grade) | 2.0 (German grade)

Minor in Computer Science

Thesis involved quantum computing and its impact on digital signature schemes